mac.schmitz@att.net • https://www.linkedin.com/in/mac-schmitz-41720252/

(678) 200-6813 • Atlanta, GA

Seasoned and resourceful high-level marketer, Executive Director, and project manager who delivers profitable solutions to drive sales, attract and maintain customers, and build a solid brand. Special talent for enhancing marketability through electronic and print marketing tools as well as clear messaging. Experienced in project management, fundraising, event planning, and managing volunteers. Team-oriented Development Officer competent in developing training processes and procedures.

- Marketing
- Project Management
- Strategic Planning & Analysis
- Communication

- Leadership
- Budgeting & Fundraising
- Staff Development
- Event Planning & Execution
- Presentation Preparation
- Research
- Content Creation and Writing
- Complex Problem Solving

# **Professional Experience**

#### The National Monuments Foundation • Atlanta, GA • September 2012 to Present

# Executive Director (February 2022 to present)

Oversees the operation, administration, programs, and strategic plan of the organization. Provides resources to the board of directors to promote organizational growth.

- Leads the organization in a manner that supports and guides the mission and vision as defined by the Board of Directors.
- Responsible for communicating effectively with the Board and providing, in a timely and accurate manner, all
  information necessary for the Board to function properly and to make informed decisions.
- Planned and managed a 4-day celebration of Ambassador Andrew Young's 90<sup>th</sup> birthday with the theme of Peace and Reconciliation. The events were broadcast by Cox Communications to 750 million people around the world and included an international interdenominational prayer sermon, a peace walk through downtown Atlanta, a museum exhibition and published coffee table book, and two fundraising galas. This resulted in the most successful fundraising event in organization history and massive publicity gain.

# **Director of Development** (July 2015 to February 2022)

Manage, organize, and coordinate all fundraising efforts for this 501(c)(3) non-profit organization as well as manage all stages of project lifecycle from inception through monitoring and closing to deliver projects that exceed expectations on timing and budget.

- Raised more than \$7.3M to date for Rodney Cook Sr. Peace Park in Atlanta, the NMF's flagship project.
- Led the development team to meet project and quarterly goals and to deliver fundraising materials, video and content creation, architectural design and drafting, and executed scheduling and travel management.
- Participant in the 2021 *Korea Global Forum for Peace* in Seoul, Korea presenting unique ideas for Korean unification based on current projects in Atlanta, resulting in significant new growth opportunities in Asia and Russia.
- Planned, organized, fundraised, and participated in the 2019 Shin Dae-yong Global Peace Institute Peace Conference in Rome, Italy. Programmed 1 week of peace-focused events for 50 international conference participants and attendees. Orchestrated a two-day peace conference at Villa Aurelia at the American Academy in Rome focused on denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula. Speakers included 8th Secretary General of the United Nations Ban Ki-moon, U.N. Security Council President Kim Sook, Former U.S. Speaker of the House Newt Gingrich. Coordinated a finale dinner at Palazzo Doria Pamphilj. Resulted in the 4th white paper provided to the U.S. President from our organization on North Korean denuclearization.
- Coordinated and raised money for the 2017 Millennium Candler Peace and Justice Prize Commission in Denmark.
   Organized 1 week of peace-focused events with final ceremony and banquet dinner a Ledreborg Palace.
- Organized and successfully raised money for the Millennium Candler Peace and Justice Prize Ceremony Gala in 2013, 2015, 2016, 2018, and 2022 in Atlanta, Georgia.

### Technology and Development Associate (September 2012 to July 2015)

- Drafted and modified design plans and blueprints for NMF projects. This included the Rodney Cook Sr. Park, John
  and John Quincy Adams Memorial, Trail of Peace, and Intercontinental Exchange entrance. Assisted with creation
  of 3D virtualization of various projects. Maintained all museum exhibition technology including troubleshooting.
- Expanded community outreach for Rodney Cook Sr. Park to move project forward with strong community support.
- Developed and executed fundraising initiatives for the foundation and its projects.
- Created and maintained all websites and collaborated with publication of the Foundation's literature and books.

### Georgia CBD Distributors • Atlanta, GA • June 2020 to December 2021

#### **Marketing Manager**

- Created and managed social media strategy and develop marketing campaigns to drive sales revenue and maximize ad spend, which increased company's gross revenue by more than 250% from Q3 202 to Q1 2021
- Led video and graphic production for successful marketing campaigns
- Established and maintained email marketing strategy via Klaviyo, SpringBot, BigCommerce, and ViralSweep
- Tracked online marketing trends, collected and analyzed data and campaign performance metrics

#### Voodoo Visionary • Atlanta, GA • January 2013 to October 2021

#### Founder, Manager, Drummer

- Founded and built from the ground up a nationally touring funk band, crowd-funded and produced 2 full-length albums and 1 EP. Co-wrote music and lyrics for all releases.
- Structured the business as an LLC, copyrighted all lyrics and music, registered songs with performing rights organizations, and set up digital distribution for all recordings across all major music platforms.
- Planned and executed successful PR campaigns for each new release through social media channels and 3<sup>rd</sup> party outlets including TV and radio performances, interviews and reviews in magazines and blogs, and performances and tours in support of each release.
- Maintained a demanding touring schedule of between 50 and 120-plus concerts annually around the United States.
- Executed marketing campaigns for every concert. Coordinate between venues, promoters, and other artists to ensure maximum ticket sales each time we perform including running campaigns on social media, Google, and local media outlets.
- Managed merchandising and branding for the band including maintaining inventory and ordering of CDs, apparel, and other merch table items as well as all posters, videos and promotional materials.
- Organized tour booking, contract writing and negotiation, show and travel logistics, travel arrangements, and business accounting.

# **Other Leadership Experience**

Executive Board, Chi Psi Fraternity Rollins Chapter • Winter Park, FL • April 2009 to 2012 Founder, Students Working to Improve Marine Sustainability (S.W.I.M.S) • Winter Park, FL • April 2009 to 2012

# **Education**

Bachelor of Arts in Environmental Studies, Minor in Spanish, Rollins College, Winter Park, FL (2012)

# **Computer Skills**

Proficient in MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Adobe Photoshop, iMovie, all major social media platforms, Salesforce, website design on Squarespace and Wix, and email marketing with MailChimp, Klaviyo, and SpringBot Experience with web development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Node.is